Yan Dai

PERSONAL DATA

DATE OF BIRTH: 27 December 1989 VISA STATUS: Resident Visa

ADDRESS: 15 Kahikatea grove, Paparangi, Wellington, New Zeland

PHONE: 021 023 82956

EMAIL: alvindaiyan@gmail.com
GITHUB: https://github.com/alvindaiyan

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I have over 5 years' experience in building enterprise and web based application. I am hard working, reliable and keen to work in a forward thinking team. I am creative, independent and a good communicator with a desire to acquire new skills as well as advance existing skills.

My aim is to work as a full stack software developer, eventually having responsibilities in software architecture, business analysis and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

a	l -	1 .
SKILL DESCRIPTION	EXPERIENCE	LEVEL
Programming Skill		
Java (J2SE, J2EE)	Paid	Advance
Go	Practical	Intermediate
AngularJS & Nodejs & Webpack & Grunt & Gulp	Paid	Advance
DATABASE PROGRAMMING		
Relational Datbase (MySQL, PostSQL)	Paid	Advance
Cassandra	Paid	Intermediate
WEB DEVELOPMENT		
SpringMVC, JAX-RS, JSP	Paid	Advance
HTML & CSS	Paid	Intermediate
Javascript & JQuery	Paid	Intermediate
DEVOPS SKILLS		
Vagrant & Docker	Pratical	Intermediate
AWS	Paid	Intermediate
Unix/Linux (Centos 7 & Ubuntu 12.04+)	Paid	Intermediate
Jenkins2	Paid	Intermediate
Project Management		
Agile Methodology	Practical	Intermediate

EDUCATION

2009-2013 Bachelor of Engineering (Hons) in Sofware Engineering,

Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington

Honours Project: "PSO for Feature Construction and Binary Classification"

Published Paper: New Representations in PSO for Feature Construction in Classification

Advisor: Prof. Mengjie ZHANG

2008-2009 Certificates in English Proficiency and Foundation Studies

Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAN 2016-CURRENT

Full Stack Software Engineer at IPAYROLL LTD, Wellington A Full Services Accounting and Payroll System

Developed customized financial report regarding of various specific requirement from clients.

Participated in developing iPayroll Restful API using Spring-Rest and developed the API doc using SpringFox, Swagger. Details can be found at http://dev.ipayroll.co.nz/.

Developed, Maintained and Code reviewed the existing iPayroll System by Java, post-gresSQL, Git and Spring framework (Prefer Intellij).

Developed Time and Attendance front end system with ES6, AngularJs 1.4, Jasimine, Gulp and webpack (Sublime Text).

Developed a plugin for Slack using Slack Webhooks, Slackbot, Java 8, gradle and Spring-hoot

MAR 2015-NOV 2016

Technical Consultant, Devops at FOODNINJA, Wellington A Local Food Delivery Service Platform

Migrated the application host to AWS.

Participate in Software Architecture Design and Quality Control.

Nov 2013-Dec 2015

Software Engineer at SYL RESEARCH LTD., Wellington

Enterprise Search Engine Using Java (SYL Platform 2.0, 2.1 and 2.5)

Developed and Optimised new Java crawler for IBM LotusNotes, doubled the crawling performance and being used commercially.

Developed a module (Java, Apache POI) for extracting embedded documents from MS Word, Excel and Powerpoint. This is used by syl 2.1, and syl 2.5 platform.

Main Developer for WordPerfect Document parsing function and used by syl 2.1 and syl 2.5 platform.

Developed a RESTful API (JAX-RS using Jersey) for metadata services in syl 2.1 and syl 2.5 platform.

JAN 2011-FEB 2012

Software Engineer at Beijing ShenZhou Aerospace Software Technology Co., Ltd, Beijing, China

Knowledge based engineering management project for China Aerospace Science $\mathcal E$ Industry Corp (CASIC)

Help with requirements analysis for the functions of knowledge acquisition, assessment of the problem, revision and evaluation system.

Developed a online document viewing system.

Research on the related algorithm such as the Genetic Programming, Support Vector Machine, Bayesian Network for data mining, search engine and Auto error detection function.

JAN 2013-MAR 2013

Software Engineer (Summer Intern) at FRONDE SYSTEMS GROUP, Wellington

Auto Billing Reporting System in Java

Requirements analysis for understanding the complex charging rules and implementing these complex rules.

Software Architecture design: designing the basic structure of the system, helping with deciding the programming language and demonstrating the software architecture to the stakeholder.

Team Management as a Scrum Master for our agile methodology.

AUG 2013-JAN 2014

Software Developer (Part-time) at PRICETECH, Wellington Web Based Applications Using .Net

Maitenance of existing Pricetech Client Applications.

Software development using C# and ASP.Net for the web-based price application. Software requirements gathering, including meeting clients, software requirements analysis

Nov 2012-Feb 2013

Research Assistant at Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington Evolutionary Computation for Data Manipulation and Using Particle Swarm Optimisation (PSO) for Feature Construction

Published Paper: PSO for Feature Construction and Binary Classification

Research and Design on the related algorithm for feature construction using PSO which is one of the very first research in this area.

Implementing the designed algorithm in Java and Recording and analysing the experiment results.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Honours Degree of Engineering in Software Engineering and Achieving a B+ average for all past four years courses.

Have published two papers for Genetic and Evolutionary Computation Conference (GECCO) 13 and EvoApps 2014.

Have developed a service-based, open-sourced instant messaging application using spare time, this project is hosted on github.

Volunteer Software Engineer at Habitat for Humanity to help with their content management system.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Technology, Reading, Programming

Being an active developer on Github.

Writing technical blogs, you can find my blog at http://alvindaiyan.github.io/

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Fluent

CHINESE: Mother tongue

REFEREES

Peter De Vocht

Former Founder & Chief Scientist

Syl Semantics

Phone: +64 (21) 0215 2225 Email: peter@peter.co.nz

Address: Level 1, Featherston Tower, 23 Waring Taylor Street, Welling-

ton, 6145 New Zealand

Wei Ren

Technical Project Lead

PriceTech Ltd

Phone: +64 21 263 5379

Email: wei.ren@pricetech.co.nz

Address: Level 4, 50 Manners Street, Wellington, New Zealand

Hongjun Wang

Project Manager

Beijing ShenZhou Aerospace Software Technology Co., Ltd

Phone: +86 10 134 011 83030 Email: wanghongjun@bjsasc.com

Address: 28 Yongfeng Road Haidian, Beijing, China